Division of Entomology Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Division of Entomology Archives
1948-2014
ENTAR.001419
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
8
two filing cabinets
These are the miscellaneous archives associated with the Division of Entomology at the Yale Peabody Museum.
Division of Entomology, Yale Peabody Museum
Biographical Sketch
The systematic collections of the Yale Peabody Museum?s Division of Entomology comprise over one million curated specimens.
Division holdings include important collections of lepidopterans, arachnids, Orthoptera, Coleoptera, water beetles and midges, and specialty collections on evolutionary themes. Recent acquisitions also include historically important collections from other institutions.
The Division also maintains a general entomological library of periodicals, books and reprints that includes coverage of arachnology donated from the Alexander Petrunkevitch Library.
Description of the Material
The archives include material such as Annual Reports, ledgers, project data etc.
Connecticut; USA; Letters; Books; Calendars; Record books; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Entomology Luncheons, 1992-2011; Series I
  - 1992-1998. Entomology Luncheon information for 1992-1998., 001428
  - 1998 - 2001. Entomology Luncheon information for 1998 - 2001., 001429
  - 2002-2006. Entomology Luncheon information for 2002-2006., 002097
  - 2007-2011. Entomology Luncheon information for 2007-2011., 002098
- Budget Reports, 1982 - 2006; Series II
  Scope and Contents
  Budget and various funding information. EST number of items = 100.
  - General Appropriations. General Appropriations Operating Statments. EST number of items = 15+., 1992-1993; 001425
  - Goelet-Cary Fund. Budget information related to the Goelet - Cary fund. EST number of items = 50+., 1981- 1992; 001423
  - Hodge Fund. Budget information related to the Hodge fund. EST number of items = 30+., 1990-1992; 001421
  - Hutchinson Fund. Budget information related to the Hutchinson fund. EST number of items = 20+., 1980-1983; 001422
  - Miscellaneous. Miscellaneous budget reports. EST number of items = 15., 001426
  - Remington Fund. Budget information related to the Remington fund. Number of items = 1., 1992; 001424
- Volunteers, 1972 - 2001; Series III
  Volunteer information for the Department of Entolomology. EST number of items = 25+.
  - 1972 -1990. Volunteer information from 1972-1990., 001431
  - 1991 - 2001. Volunteer information from 1990 - 2001., 001432
- Collection Priorities, Series IV
  - CLR Lists. Charles Lee Remingtons lists of specimens to be aquired by the Yale Peabody museum. Number of items = 6., 001434
- Entomology Library, Series V
  - Lending Lists. Lending lists and available reprints from the Entomology Library. EST number of items = 25., 001437
  - Library Requests. EST number of items = 30+., 001438
  - Main Components of Entomlogy Library. Main components of the entomology library include the Hessel library and the Jones library est number of items = 30+., 001436
- Annual Reports, 1948-1999; Series VI
  - 1948-1959. EST number of items = 10., 001402
  - 1960-1964. EST number of items = 10+., 001440
  - 1965-1969. EST number of items = 10., 001441
  - 1970-1974. EST number of items = 10+., 001442
  - 1975-1979. EST number of items = 10., 001443
  - 1980-1984. EST number of items = 5., 001444
  - 1985-1989., 001448
  - 1990-1994. Number of items = 2., 001445
  - 1995-1999. Number of items = 3., 001446
  - 2000-2004., 001904
  - 2005-2009., 001905
  - 2010-2014., 001906
  - Pre -1948., 001903
- Mark & Recapture Data, Series VII
  - Hemileuca. EST number of items = 25+., 1978-1979; 001531
  - Hesperia., 2000-2002; 001719
  - Karner Blues., 1978-1992; 001532
  - Regal Fritillary., 1983-1987; 001533
- Xerces Society, Series VIII
  Department of Entomology archives relating to the Xerces Society.
  - 4th of July Butterfly Count. 4th of July Butterfly count sheets and data. Count announcment is oversized, in library., 001711
  - Annual Meetings., 001710
  - Member Lists., 1973-1980; 001709
- Connecticut Butterfly Atlas Project, Series IX
  CBAP
  - Data. CBAP Data; Miscellaneous, Uconn, Demasi, Maier (Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station)., 001714
  - Meeting Minutes., 001713
- Ledgers, Series X
  - Dartmouth. Dartmouth ledgers., 002669
    - 1: 1-8219. Internal re number - 122599, 002670
    - 2: 8220-16332. Internal re number - 122600, 002671
    - 3:16333-24522. Internal re number - 122601, 002672
    - 4: 24533-33304. Internal re number - 122602, 002673
    - 5: 33305-41529. Internal re number - 122603, 002674
    - 6: 41530-49414. Internal re number - 122604, 002675
    - 7: 49415-56544. Internal re number - 122605, 002676
    - Locke. Internal re number - 122606, 002677
  - Insecta., 002684
    - A: 1-4175. Internal re number 122614., 002685
    - B: 4176-5629. Internal re number 122615., 002686
    - C: 13-260,2086-2300, 2301-2431. Internal re number 122616., 002687
    - D: 2500-5035,4750-5340. Internal re number 122617., 002688
  - LEPH., 002678
    - 1. Internal re number 122607., 002679
    - 2. Internal re number 122608., 002680
    - 3. Internal re number 122609., 002681
    - 3. Internal re number 122610., 002682
    - 5. Internal re number 122611., 002683
  - Miscellaneous., 002689
    - Bishop. Internal re number 122612, 1936-1938; 002691
    - Pratt. Internal re number 122613., 002690
- Grants, Series XI
  - American Philosophy Society Grant., 1955-1956; 002695
  - Guggenheim Grant. Oxford., 1958-1959; 002696
  - NSF "Collections Curation" GB-2581 Documentation & Finances., 1964-1969; 002709
  - NSF "Collections Curation" GB-2581 Proposals & Reports., 1964-1969; 002708
  - NSF "Evolutionary Processes" G-12350 Documentation & Finances., 1960-1962; 002702
  - NSF "Evolutionary Processes" G-12350 Proposals & Reports., 1960-1962; 002701
  - NSF "Evolutionary Processes" G-1739 Documentation & Finances., 1955-1957; 002698
  - NSF "Evolutionary Processes" G-1739 Proposals & Reports., 1955-1957; 002697
  - NSF "Evolutionary Processes" G-23781 Documentation & Finances., 1962-1964; 002704
  - NSF "Evolutionary Processes" G-23781 Proposals & Finances., 1962-1964; 002703
  - NSF "Evolutionary Processes" G-3830 Documentation & Finances., 1957-1960; 002700
  - NSF "Evolutionary Processes" G-3830 Proposals & Reports., 1957-1960; 002699
  - NSF "Evolutionary Processes" GB-3763 Documentation & Finances., 1965-1966; 002706
  - NSF "Evolutionary Processes" GB-3763 Propsals & Reports., 1965-1966; 002705
  - Other Research Grants/Trips., 1964-1965; 002707
  - U.S. Navey Alaska Grant NR 307-021., 1952-1953; 002694
- Multimedia, Series XII
  - Newspaper Clippings., 002767
  - Photographs., 002714
  - Slides. Miscellaneous Slides., 002768
- Demonstration Drawers, Series XIII
  Assemblages of specimens that exemplify various evolutionary, ecological, and other principles
  - Periodical or 17-year cicadas (Magicicada septendecim). Inlcudes a variety of specimens from Connecticut Broods II and XI, from 1843 to the present, and newspaper clipping from 1860 describing the emergence in New York., 002778
  - Structural coloration in insects., 002782
  - Gynandromorphs., 002783
  - Inflated Lepidoptera caterpillars., 002784
  - Original box of insects used in avian taste test experiments, from Frank Morton Jones collection., 002785